Eric Huang

Miami, Florida, United States



erichuang676@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/eric-huang-51a5481ab

Summary

As a Senior Mobile App Developer, I have proven and solid experience in mobile app development. Over 7 years of deep mobile app development experience plus additional years of full-cycle experience in multiple roles and environments, including healthcare, fitness, social networking, financial, medical, and management.

Whether you just need capable manpower, need to hire someone for a one-off or long term task, or want a brand new app, I would be glad to step in and help!

My Skills:

- Native Mobile(iOS&Android): Objective-C, Swift, Core-Java, Kotlin, C#
- Hybrid: React Native, Ionic, Expo, Flutter, NativeScript, Xamarin
- React, Angular, Node
- Team work: Trello, Jira, Asana
- Source code Management: Github, Bitbucket
- Firebase, AWS, Azure DevOps

Thanks for reviewing!

Experience



Senior Mobile App Developer

Capital One

Mar 2020 - Dec 2022 (2 years 10 months)

- Worked on the mobile payments app Spark Pay which enabled merchants to take payments on the go
- Architected and implemented key payment features in the app
- Coordinated with the product team on the app roadmap
- Led Swift migration of the project from Objective-C



Android Developer

Kinedu

Jul 2018 - Mar 2020 (1 year 9 months)

- Developed the Kinedu Android app from scratch that has grown to over a million downloads and 250k monthly active users.
- Nominee for the 2019 Google Play Awards for "Standout Well-Being App"

Senior iOS Developer

Shopkick, a Trax Company

Jun 2017 - Jun 2018 (1 year 1 month)

- Worked on the Shopkick app which uses iBeacons to drive traffic to retail stores

- Architected and implemented features that helped improve engagement and retention in the app

Education

University of Miami

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science Sep 2014 - Aug 2018

Skills

iOS Development • Android Development • React Native • Swift (Programming Language) • Objective-C • Java • Kotlin • Android SDK • NativeScript • Flutter